# Karthikeyan Ramani (1) Featured

Seeking roles in Software Engineering, Software Development, Application Development, Project Management, Change Management, Defect Management, Quality Management, Requirement Gathering, Core Java, SQL



Current Location: Chennai Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 7 Month(s)

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad Notice Period: 15 Days or less

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming / Highest Degree: MBA/PGDM [Leadership through

Maintenance Analytics and Decision Sciences]

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Key Skills: Software Developer, Software Engineering, Software Development, Application Development, Project Management, Change Management, Defect Management, Quality Management, Requirement Gathering, Core Java, SQL

Server, Eclipse, Python, WinSCP, jQuery, Maven, Putty, HTML

Server, Eclipse, Python, WinSCP, iQuery, Maven, Putty, HTML

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Modified: 20-Jan-21 Last Active: 20-Jan-21

#### Summary

Having 4.7 years(57 months) of IT experience in developing using technologies Java / J2EE, Oracle SQL, MS SQL Server, Spark Technology, Scala, Pyspark, Angular JS and Python.

Hands on experience in Core Java, JDBC, Servlets, JSP.

Experience in version control using SVN, MKS.

Experience in Oracle database.

Good Team player and also have ability to work independently.

Adaptive to learn new technologies.

### Work Experience

Mu Sigma as Trainee Apprentice Leader

Feb 2020 to Sep 2020

Accenture as Application Development Analyst

Apr 2018 to Jan 2019

Client - Telstra - (Dec 2018) I worked in PCF and Lambda Micro services using Spring tool suite(STS). I developed some simple spring boot applications. Team size: 10

Role: Team Member

Responsibility: I need to know about Telstra account and its function

Client - BCBSMI (Blue Cross Blue Shield of Michigan) - (Oct 2018 - Nov 2018) - Worked in spark technology and big data

in HDFS Server and EDGENODE. Team size: 6

Role: Team Member

Responsibility: I need to supervise few juniors and ensure proper transfer of data from HDFS Server to EDGENODE with list of customer health details who have subscribed to BCBSMI Insurance.

Client - State Farm Insurance - (July 2018 - Sep 2018) - I worked on short stories for each sprint in Angular JS Platform to perform UI changes on client's web page. Team size: 5

Role: Team Member

Responsibility: I need to perform a stint for each sprint wherein i designed the State Farm Insurance web page as per client's requirement and update the daily progress over scrum call.

Client Societe Generale - (April 2018 - June 2018) - I was part of French hub and got trained in French language till A2 level.

Role: Team Member

Responsibility: I have to scale up in French proficiency to intereact with French Clients from Societe Generale regarding business requirements.

#### Wipro Technologies as Project Engineer

Mar 2017 to Mar 2018

Project Name Straight through Payment(STP)

Description This is one of the major section of payment category of the Lloyds banking project. It involves various transactions happening within and outwards Lloyds banking using various payment services such as Faster Payment Services(FPS) and Common Banking System(CBS)

Domain Banking - Lloyds Banking Group(LBG) Duration (03/2017) - (03/2018)

Role Team Member Team Size

Environment

Eclipse, Maven, IBM integration tool kit, putty, Message Queue, Winscp

Responsibilities I Was responsible for working on Java changes in the coding part of the STP platform. I Was also responsible for performing smoke testing in an integrated payment service like STP for faster payment service.

#### Tech Mahindra Limited as Associate Software Engineer

Jan 2014 to Feb 2016

Description MLQS is a front-end intranet online quoting system for Marine Lubricants. It handles quoting of prices of various Marine Lubricant products. The application is mostly used by Business Analysts and Managers to review the price changes of lubricant products over time in various locations.

Domain Oil and Gas - Chevron Duration (06/2014) - (08/2014)

Role Team Member Team Size 6

**Environment** 

Eclipse, Net beans, Mysql, HTML

Responsibilities I Was responsible in working on Change Requests and completing them as per the Schedule.

Project Name Asia-Pacific Application Support(APAC)

Description This support task involves the maintenance of following applications: Access Solution, Work Request

Process, Wet Stock Management and StarCard Reporting, with real time monitoring of scheduled tasks.

Domain Oil and Gas - Chevron Duration 09/2014 - 06/2015

Team Member Team Size Role

**Environment** 

Eclipse, Net beans, Mysgl, HTML

Responsibilities As part of support activities, it involves in fixing issues reported by users and providing enhancements to eliminate recurring issues and work in enhancement tasks.

Additional Information The duties also include real-time monitoring of scheduled tasks in a daily basis.

Project Name

Description The support task involves handling ongoing work load in Fiber Chain for KPN Netherlands project.

Domain Telecom - KPN Duration 10/2015 - 02/2016

Role Team Member Team Size 6

**Environment** 

KPN WSIP and WBA portal.

Responsibilities The support task involves handling ongoing work load in Fiber Chain for KPN Netherlands project. Additional Information 
Currently multiple migrations are in progress and everyday multiple tickets/incidents opened for technical exceptions and stuck orders. As part of operations activity, these tickets should be solved with solution available, if not perform root cause analysis and identify issue causing the problem with possible solution to progress the order. Applications are in TIBCO (BW, Iprocess) and most of the activities are performed using TIBCO Clever, GEMS, SOAP.

#### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Information and Communication Technology) from SASTRA University, Tanjore in 2012

PG: MBA/PGDM (Leadership through Analytics and Decision Sciences) from T A PAI INSTITUTE OF MANAGEMENT in 2020

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Oracle Database SQL certified expert.

Oracle PL/SQL Developer certified associate.

Oracle certified professional, Java SE 6 programmer.

## IT Skills

| Skill Name                          | Version | Last Used | Experience |
|-------------------------------------|---------|-----------|------------|
| C, C++                              |         |           |            |
| JAVA                                |         |           |            |
| Oracle 9i,11g, SQL Server 2005/2008 |         |           |            |
| MS-Access 2003/2000                 |         |           |            |
| Eclipse, Putty,HTML                 |         |           |            |
| WinSCP,jQuery,Maven,                |         |           |            |

## Languages Known

| Language | Proficiency | Read | Write | Speak |
|----------|-------------|------|-------|-------|
| English  | Expert      |      |       |       |
| French   | Proficient  |      |       |       |
| Tamil    | Expert      |      |       |       |
| Hindi    | Beginner    |      |       |       |

#### **Affirmative Action**

Physically Challenged: No

#### **Work Authorization**

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time